# Ananda Kevin Refaldo Sariputra, B. C. Sc.

Tangerang, Indonesia | Linkedin | Github | Kaggle | +6281398359277 | anandakevinsariputra@gmail.com

## PERSONAL SUMMARY

As a software engineer with 4 years of experience, I specialize in designing and implementing backend systems using Spring Boot, Bash, and Spring Batch. My expertise extends to front-end stacks such as Angular, React, and Bootstrap. I excel in consulting user requirements and am proficient in Machine Learning, especially Deep Learning. I'm also familiar with cloud computing services in AWS & GCP. Seeking opportunities to contribute my skills and drive innovation.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Bank Central Asia Tangerang, Indonesia

Mid-Level Full Stack Software Engineer, General Ledger (GL) Team Junior Full Stack Software Engineer, General Ledger Team Information Technology Intern, General Ledger Team July 2022 – Present April 2020 - June 2022 October 2019 - March 2020

# **Technology Used**

- Mainframe (COBOL, JCL, Connect Direct, TSO, DITTO, VSAM and QSAM datasets)
- Database (PostgreSQL, Oracle PL/SQL, SQLPlus)
- Backend (Java Spring, Spring Boot)
- Frontend (Angular, Typescript, JS, JQuery, HTML, CSS)
- Dependency Tools (Maven, Gradle)
- Message broker (ActiveMQ)
- Cloud Service (OCP (Openshift Cloud Platform))
- Version Control System (Gitlab)
- Automation (Control-M (Monitoring Only))

## **Technical Contribution & Projects**

- Consult, negotiate, plan, and manage projects
- Build, deploy, maintain, document, and monitor Features in GL and its dependencies
- Mentor teammates on technical aspects, projects, and business processes
- Prepared the necessary checklists and technical infrastructure and leading the team through the execution of GL's simulation and real End of Year in 2021 2023
- Identified and resolved complex technical issues across multiple programs and platforms, reducing critical errors by 50% and improving user experience by implementing innovative solutions.
- Developed user management system in GL utilizing OAuth 2.0 in 2022
- Rewrote 50% of team legacy batch programs previously in Mainframe (COBOL) to SQL
- Optimized numerous batch programs (e.g. Reducing process time from 45 60 to 1 5 minutes process, mostly in SQL)
- Architected and integrated system between GL and other parties via batch interface and APIs, implementing logging and idempotency management system
- Developed dynamic parameter system in 2020 & 2021, revamped it in 2023
- Wrote comprehensive team encyclopedia covering business process, data flow and technical guides

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bina Nusantara University**

Jakarta, Indonesia

School Of Computer Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.92)

August 2017 - September 2021

• Thesis: Object Detection Model for Web Based Physical Distancing Detector in Indonesia using Deep Learning. (Currently on going for Journal Publication)

#### **PROJECTS**

- Built three projects with each solving a problem in a time series data, NLP Article Topic Classifier, and Bird Image Classifier through Dicoding Course, related to IDCamp Scholarship, 2024
- Published personal arsenal of Competitive Programming Solution in GitHub, 2019 Present
- Open-Source Project on Solana Cookbook Indonesian Translation, 2022

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

- Intermediate Machine Learning Course, Dicoding, Related to IDCamp Scholarship, 2024
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, related to AWS Re/Start, 2023
- Learnt Google Cloud and its features though Juara GCP event, Google Cloud Skill Boost, 2023
- Apple iOS Foundation Program, related to BINUS University, 2019

#### **SKILLS**

## **Technical stacks worked with:**

- Programming (Java, C/C++, Python, COBOL, JCL, Flutter)
- Database Management (Oracle PL/SQL, SQLLite, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server)
- NoSQL Database Management (MongoDB)
- Version Control System (Git, Github, Gitlab)
- Web Development (Web Fundamentals, JQuery, Angular, JS, Typescript)
- Back End Development (Spring, Spring Boot)
- Containerization (Docker)
- Message Broker (Kafka)
- Cloud Technologies (AWS, GCP)
- Scripting (Bash, Batch)
- Machine Learning & Deep Learning (Tensorflow, Keras), Object Detection (Darknet, YOLO)

#### **Soft Skills:**

- Problem Solving: Analyzed complex issues and devised efficient solutions
- Team Collaboration: Collaborated with business analysts, testers, product managers and other cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software
- Adaptability: Successfully adapted to changing project requirements and technologies
- Time Management: Prioritized tasks effectively to meet project deadlines

Language: Professional English (C2) and Native Indonesian speaker

#### **AWARDS**

- Exceeded Expectations Appraisal on 2021 Performance Review, Bank Central Asia, 2022
- Code Jam Round 1 Contestant, Google, 2020
- UNY Calculus National Finalist, State University of Yogyakarta, 2018
- 1st place in Individual and Group High School Math Contest, HIMMA Sriwijaya University, 2017
- Senior High School National Math Olympiad Finalist, Ministry of Education and Culture, 2016
- ISMOC Math Top 20 National Level Finalist, Surya University, 2016
- Bronze Medalist at Elementary National Math Olympiad, Ministry of Education and Culture, 2011

## **SCHOLARSHIPS**

• Intermediate IDCamp Machine Learning Scholarship, Indosat Ooredoo Hutchison IDCamp, 2024

- AWS Re/Start Program, Scholarship for learning AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification, 2023
- Bachelor Completion Scholarship (Rest of 1.5 years), Bank Central Asia, 2020 2021
- PPTI Scholarship (Bachelor's Full Scholarship for 2.5 years), Bank Central Asia, 2017 2020
- Full Scholarship, Ignatius Global Senior High School, 2014 2017
- Enrolled on acceleration class, 2 years scholarship, Xaverius 1 Junior High School, 2012 2014

# LEADERSHIP, SPEAKER & ACTIVITY EXPERIENCE

# Bangkit Academy 2023 By Google, GoTo, Traveloka

Online

Cloud Computing Instructor H1 & H2

February 2023 – December 2023

• Engaged students in Cloud Computing Topic, received average rating of 4.23 in H1 and 4.74 in H2

Project Capstone Advisor H1 & H2

February 2023 – December 2023

- Guided students in Cloud Computing, Machine Learning & Project Management
- Provided clarity through clear explanations, fostering better understanding
- Received average rating of 4.88 in H1 (from 4 groups) and 4.73 in H2 (from 5 groups)

# **BINUS Bekasi University**

Online

Spearker of Git & Github: First Time Users

December 2022

• Shared insights on Git and Github to the first semester students of Binus Bekasi University